

Summary _

Professional with 2.5 years of work experience, have worked with different teams in collaboration with experienced workforce to work towards customer issues by bringing together the skill sets in delivering best performance and service to the client.

Work Experience _____

Ericsson Noida

Integration Engineer Feb. 2018 - May 2020

- Preparing MOPs and macros to create efficiency for quality delivery in short duration
- Weekly Reports, Tracker, and Auditing of pre-site database to meet the customer objectives
- · Pre-commissioning and Post-Commissioning for Samsung/Ericsson new sites and new carrier for LTE (TDD, FDD) and CDMA
- Integration for Samsung and Ericsson LTE (700, 800, 1900, 2500 MHz), CDMA (800,1900 MHz) sites
- · Live Network Troubleshoots of different technologies in coordination with Tower crew, Field engineer and Back-haul Team
- Traffic Analysis and Performance Management of existing network using various key performance indicators
- Validation of RF parameters and physical attributes of LTE and CDMA Sites

Ericsson Noida

CLOUD ENGINEER May 2020 - July 2020

- Launching Amazon EC2 instances using Amazon Images (Linux/Ubuntu) and optimizing instances with respect to specific applications.
- Creating alarms in Cloud Watch service for monitoring server performance, CPU Utilization, disk usage etc
- Creating and managing users, and groups in Linux.
- Used Python programming language to develop efficient network within the company.

Technical Skills

- AWS Services: S3, EC2, ELB, VPC, EBS, IAM, Cloudwatch, CloudTrail, Glacier, SNS, SQS
- · Operating System: Linux and Windows
- Monitoring Tools: CloudWatch
- languages: Python, C, C++, MySQL, Shell scripting

Education

B.Tech. in Electronics and Communication Engineering

Jaipur, Rajasthan

POORNIMA INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY

2013 - 2017

Post Graduate Diploma in Computer Application

Amritsar, Punjab

GURU NANAK DEV UNIVERSITY

2018 - 2019

Certifications

AWS Certified solutions architect associate

SAA-C02

ISSUED BY AMAZON WEB SERVICES TRAINING AND CERTIFICATION

Oct, 2020

- Earners of this certification have a comprehensive understanding of AWS services and technologies. They demonstrated the ability to build secure and robust solutions using architectural design principles based on customer requirements. Badge owners are able to strategically design well-architected distributed systems that are scalable, resilient, efficient, and fault-tolerant.
- includes skills on AWS web services, Cloud infrastructure, Cloud Architecture, Cloud data, AWS cloud services

5G RAN certified associateIssued by Ericsson through Pearson Vue tests

Pearson Vue/ Ericsson

• Earners of this certification have demonstrated basic knowledge, skills, and abilities necessary to achieve a conceptual understanding of 5G RAN architecture, functions, technologies, and 5G RAN fundamentals.

• includes skills: 5G RAN architecture, 5G deployment strategies, 5G RAN air interface and propagation, Ericsson 5G RAN solutions

SHIVAM BHASKAR · RESUMÉ